(Sid) Siddhant Khanna Edmonton, AB, Canada Mobile: 647-760-4086

Email: siddhant.khanna@gmail.com | Website

### PROFILE:

Studying Computing Science at University of Alberta. I am interested in learning and gaining new experiences. Always trying to improve and continuously learn from my failures. I am hardworking, disciplined, introspective and a team player. Experienced in Object Oriented Programming (OOP) and test-driven development. Able to adapt in new working environments and love to socialize with people.

#### **EDUCATION:**

BSc. Specialization in Computing Science BSc. Computer Science

**High School** 

**PROGRAMMING SKILLS:** 

- Python
- JAVA
- C/C++
- SQL (sqlite3 / MySQL)

## **OTHER EXPERIENCE:**

- GitHub Version Control System
- Android Studio / Eclipse

#### **SOME EXPERIENCE:**

HTML5 / CSS / PHP

University of Alberta (2015 - present) Edmonton, AB York University (2014- 2015) Toronto, ON Sanskriti School (2000-2014) New Delhi, India

- Javascript
- Bootstrap Framework
- MATLAB/Assembly
- CUDA C

#### **CURRENTLY LEARNING/COURSEWORK:**

- ReactJS
- Cloud Storage
- REST API
- Django Framework

**PROJECTS:** (GitHub.com/Sidkhanna96)

Web Design (Personal Project): GitHub -- Link

(July 2018) Edmonton, AB

Created Personal Website using HTML5, CSS3 and Bootstrap 4 Framework. Sidkhanna96.github.io/MyWebsite.

#### Database Management Projects (Group of 2): GitHub - Link

(Jan – April 2018) Edmonton, AB

- Parsing through xml file to create database. Implementing triggers.
- Using SQL in C and python extract information and perform calculation. Extract information from website.

#### Software Engineering (Collaborated with Group of 5): GitHub - Link

(Sept. - Dec 2017) Edmonton, AB

HabitTracker Android App – Mobile app for tracking user habits

Developed using Android Studio and Java.

- Implemented Junit Testing. Conversion of data into JSON.
- MVC architecture and OOP

# **RELEVENT COURSEWORK:**

- Computation I & II (CMPUT 174/175), Programming Methodology (CMPUT 201), Software Engineering I (CMPUT 301), Software Process & Product Management (CMPUT 401)
- Intro. to Cryptography (CMPUT 210), Security in a Networked World (CMPUT 333)
- Introduction to File and Database Management (CMPUT 291), Database Management Systems (CMPUT 391)
- Language Fluency: English, Hindi

### **ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE:**

**Best-Buy: Sales Specialist** 

(August-October 2014) Etobicoke, ON

- Analyzed and asses the needs and requirement of each customer and find the right product that fit their needs
- Consistently updated my knowledge of technology as products evolved

**Reliance Future Group:** 

(December 2013) New Delhi, India

• Asset Inventory Management

## Aditya Birla Retail:

(June 2013) New Delhi, India

• Asset Inventory Management

# Sanskriti School Pravah Program:

(May 2013) New Delhi, India

• Lived in a village and helped locals in farming and manufacturing handmade products.